T.S. Gold Family Papers 1982.0002
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
T.S. Gold Family Papers
undated, 1800-1907
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
1982.0002
14 Linear Feet
Theodore Sedgwick Gold was born in Madison, New York. T.S. Gold graduated from Yale College in 1838 and then spent four years studying and teaching at academies in Goshen and Waterbury. He moved to Cornwall in 1842 to pursue a career in farming. Mr. Gold was a trustee of the Storrs Agricultural School from 1881 to 1901 and took an active role in promoting the school's growth and development throughout his lifetime.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Acquisition Information
The T.S. Gold Family Papers were donated to the University of Connecticut Library in August 1982 by Ralph C. Gold of Ottumwa, Iowa.
Arrangement
Series I: T.S. Gold (undated, 1809-1906) is composed of personal papers compiled by Mr. Gold. The series includes seven subseries: Correspondence, Writings of T.S. Gold, Storrs Agricultural School, Memorabilia, Business, Printed Material and Condolences. Correspondence (1840-1906) contains incoming correspondence regarding Mr. Gold's personal and business affairs and is arranged chronologically. Writings of T.S. Gold (1844-1905) includes notes, lectures, speeches and a few published articles. This subseries is arranged alphabetically by title or subject. Storrs Agricultural School (1884-1899) is a small subseries, arranged alphabetically, containing financial and legal papers and printed materials. Memorabilia contains positive print photographs, engravings and illustrations, newsclippings and personal effects collected by T.S. Gold. Business (1859-1904) is a limited subseries containing bills, receipts and other statements regarding Mr. Gold's personal affairs. Also included are records of the Housatonic Valley Milk Association. Printed Material (1867-1885) includes pamphlets, brochures, clippings and advertisements from various organizations in which Mr. Gold expressed an interest. Those materials not arranged by type are arranged by subject (i.e. agriculture in Connecticut). Condolences (1906) contains correspondence received by the family regarding T.S. Gold's death.
Series II: Gold Family (1809-1907) is composed of personal papers and subject files compiled by Gold family members. The series is arranged in seven subseries by family member: Gold Family, Hezikiah Gold, Phoebe Gold, Dr. Samuel Wadsworth Gold, Charles L. Gold, Franz Von Puttkamer, and General John Sedgwick. Gold Family includes memorabilia, correspondence, legal documents, and historical materials regarding the Gold and Cleveland families and is arranged by subject. Hezikiah Gold (1810-1847) includes incoming correspondence and bills and receipts and is arranged by type of material. Phoebe Gold (1823-1850) is composed of incoming correspondence that is arranged chronologically. Dr. Samuel Wadsworth Gold, MD (1809-1864) includes correspondence, bills and printed material and is arranged by type of material. Charles L. Gold is composed of one file of personal papers. Franz Von Puttkamer (1885-1907) contains correspondence, legal and financial records, and bills and receipts. It is arranged chronologically. The subseries concerns Mr. Von Puttkamer's estate, of which T.S. Gold was executor. General John Sedgwick (1839-1892) includes correspondence, printed material, orders and receipts and invitation responses regarding the memorial service held for General Sedgwick, who was a relative of the Gold family. The subseries is arranged by type.
Series III: Newspapers (1800-1901) were collected by T.S. Gold and contain predominantly 19th century local and agricultural publications. Most of the newspapers contain articles regarding agriculture, the Gold family, and organizations to which Mr. Gold belonged or other matters of interest to Mr. Gold. The series is arranged alphabetically. The newspapers are in fragile condition and some particularly fragile items may not be available to researchers.
Biography
Theodore Sedgwick Gold was born 2 March 1818 in Madison, New York, the son of Dr. Samuel Wadsworth Gold and Phoebe Cleveland. Mr. Gold was married to Caroline E. Lockwood of Bridgeport in 1843. They had three children - Eleanor Gold Hubbard, Rebecca Gold Cornell and Caroline Gold Gibson - before Mrs. Gold died in 1857. In 1859, Mr. Gold married Emma Tracey Baldwin of Rockville. They had four children - Alice Gold Puttkamer, Martha Gold Morgan, Charles Gold and Dr. James Gold.
T.S. Gold graduated from Yale College in 1838 and then spent four years studying and teaching at academies in Goshen and Waterbury. He moved to Cornwall in 1842 to pursue a career in farming. In 1845, along with his father, T.S. Gold founded the Cream Hill Agricultural School at his farm in West Cornwall, Connecticut. He continued to teach there for 24 years.
Mr. Gold was an active patron of many state agricultural endeavors. He was a founding member of the Connecticut State Agricultural Society beginning in 1853. In 1866 he was appointed secretary of the newly created Connecticut Board of Agriculture and served in that capacity for several years.
Connecticut Soldiers' Orphans' Home, located in Mansfield, Connecticut, and served as its secretary until 1874. During this same time, Mr. Gold combined his interests in farming and Connecticut history and wrote a history of Cornwall that was published in 1877.
Mr. Gold was a trustee of the Storrs Agricultural School from 1881 to 1901 and took an active role in promoting the school's growth and development throughout his lifetime. He was a member of the Board of Control of the Connecticut Agricultural Experiment Station since its establishment in 1877. Mr. Gold was also a member of numerous agricultural and historical associations.
T.S. Gold died at his home in Cornwall on 19 March 1906.
Custodial History
The papers were kept by family members in Cornwall, Connecticut, until their transfer to Ralph C. Gold of Ottumwa, Iowa.
Scope and Content
The collection contains personal papers, notes, lectures, speeches, published articles, financial and legal papers, and printed materials, photographs, engravings and illustrations, newsclippings pamphlets, brochures, advertisements, memorabilia, correspondence and historical materials regarding the Gold and Cleveland families. Also included is information and publications concerning the Storrs Agricultural School (SAS), the Housatonic Valley Milk Association as well as other organizations of interest to the Gold families.
Professional associations; Personal papers; Hartford (inhabited place); Storrs (inhabited place); Trade associations; Journalism; Decedents' estates; Clippings (information artifacts); Massachusetts (state); Litchfield (inhabited place); Cornwall (inhabited place); Agricultural colleges; Madison (inhabited place); Springfield (inhabited place); Children--Services for; Waterbury (Conn.); Winsted (inhabited place); Agricultural experiment stations; Societies; Photographs; Publications (documents); Financial Records; Agriculture; Farmers; Sag Harbor (inhabited place); Administrative records; Correspondence; Connecticut (state); New England (general region); Local history; Personal narratives; New York (inhabited place); Orphanages; Education; Newspapers; Twentieth century.; Boston (Mass.); Nineteenth century; Universities and colleges
- Series I: T.S. Gold, undated, 1809-1906
  Manuscripts (document genre); Connecticut (state)
  - Correspondence
    - Personal: incoming, undated (Box 1:, Folder 1-2)
    - Personal: incoming, 1840-1856 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
    - Personal: incoming, 1857-1858 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
    - Personal: incoming, 1859-1860 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
    - Personal: incoming, 1866-1871 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
    - Personal: incoming, 1872 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
    - Personal: incoming, 1873 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
    - Personal: incoming, 1874-1875 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
    - Personal: incoming, 1876 January - May (Box 1:, Folder 10)
    - Personal: incoming, 1876 June - December (Box 1:, Folder 11)
    - Personal: incoming, 1877-1879 (Box 1:, Folder 12)
    - Personal: incoming, 1880 January - June (Box 1:, Folder 13)
    - Personal: incoming, 1880 July - December (Box 1:, Folder 14)
    - Personal: incoming, 1881 January - April (Box 1:, Folder 15)
    - Personal: incoming, 1881 May - June (Box 1:, Folder 16)
    - Personal: incoming, 1881 July (Box 1:, Folder 17)
    - Personal: incoming, 1881 August (Box 2:, Folder 18)
    - Personal: incoming, 1881 September - December (Box 2:, Folder 19)
    - Personal: incoming, 1882 (Box 2:, Folder 20)
    - Personal: incoming, 1884 January - May (Box 2:, Folder 21)
    - Personal: incoming, 1884 June - October (Box 2:, Folder 22)
    - Personal: incoming, 1884 November (Box 2:, Folder 23)
    - Personal: incoming, 1884 December (Box 2:, Folder 24)
    - Personal: incoming, 1885-1887 (Box 2:, Folder 25)
    - Personal: incoming, 1888-1901 (Box 2:, Folder 26)
    - Personal: incoming, 1902 (Box 2:, Folder 27)
    - Personal: incoming, 1903 (Box 2:, Folder 28)
    - Personal: incoming, 1904 (Box 2:, Folder 29)
    - Personal: incoming, 1905-1906 (Box 2:, Folder 30)
    - Christmas quotation calendar, 1902-1904 (Box 2:, Folder 31)
    - B.F. Koons, 1884 (Box 2:, Folder 32)
    - Charles Storrs, 1884 (Box 2:, Folder 33)
    - L.P. Chamberlain, 1884-1885 (Box 2:, Folder 34)
    - George W. Flint, 1898-1901 (Box 2:, Folder 35)
    - Storrs Agricultural School/Connecticut, 1889 (Box 2:, Folder 36)
    - Connecticut Agricultural College, 1900-1905
    - Business: incoming, 1857-1871 (Box 3:, Folder 37)
    - Business: incoming, 1872 January - July (Box 3:, Folder 38)
    - Business: incoming, 1872 August - December (Box 3:, Folder 39)
    - Business: incoming, 1873-1875 (Box 3:, Folder 40)
    - Business: incoming, 1876 January - August (Box 3:, Folder 41)
    - Business: incoming, 1876 September - December (Box 3:, Folder 42)
    - Business: incoming, 1877 (Box 3:, Folder 43)
    - Business: incoming, 1880 Jan-Jun (Box 3:, Folder 44)
    - Business: incoming, 1880 July - December (Box 3:, Folder 45)
    - Business: incoming, 1881 January - April (Box 3:, Folder 46)
    - Business: incoming, 1881 May - June (Box 3:, Folder 47)
    - Business: incoming, 1881 July (Box 3:, Folder 48)
    - Business: incoming, 1881 August (Box 3:, Folder 49)
    - Business: incoming, 1881 September - October (Box 3:, Folder 50)
    - Business: incoming, 1882-1883 (Box 3:, Folder 51)
    - Business: incoming, 1884 January - August (Box 3:, Folder 52)
    - Business: incoming, 1884 September - October (Box 3:, Folder 53)
    - Business: incoming, 1884 November (Box 3:, Folder 54)
    - Business: incoming, 1884 December; 1982-0002/Series1:Correspondence/Box4:55 (Box 4, Folder 55)
      Correspondence; Gold, Theodore S. (Theodore Sedgwick), 1818-1906
    - Business: incoming, 1885-1897; 1982-0002/Series1:Correspondence/Box4:56 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Business: incoming, 1898-1900; 1982-0002/Series1:Correspondence/Box4:57 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Business: incoming, 1901-1902; 1982-0002/Series1:Correspondence/Box4:58 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Business: incoming, 1903; 1982-0002/Series1:Correspondence/Box4:59 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Business: Incoming, 1904 January - February; 1982-0002/Series1:Correspondence/Box4:60 (Box 4:, Folder 60, Box-folder 4:60)
    - Business: incoming, 1904 March - May; 1982-0002/Series1:Correspondence/Box4:61 (Box 4:, Folder 61, Box-folder 4:61)
    - Business: incoming, 1904 June - December; 1982-0002/Series1:Correspondence/Box4:62 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Writing of T.S. Gold
    - Untitled, 1844-1897; 1982-0002/Series2:Writings/Box4:63 (Box-folder 4:63)
      writings (documents)
    - Agriculture, 1878-1900; 1982-0002/Series2:Writings/Box4:64 (Box-folder 4:64)
      writings (documents); Agriculture
    - Agriculture, 1887; 1982-0002/Series2:Writings/Box4:65 (Box-folder 4:65)
    - Agriculture, 1892-1900; 1982-0002/Series2:Writings/Box4:66 (Box-folder 4:66)
    - Untitled, undated; 1982-0002/Series2:Writings/Box4:67 (Box-folder 4:67)
    - Untitled, undated; 1982-0002/Series2:Writings/Box4:68 (Box-folder 4:68)
    - Untitled, undated; 1982-0002/Series2:Writings/Box4:69 (Box 4:69, Box-folder 4:69)
    - Barns, undated; 1982-0002/Series2:Writings/Box4:70 (Box 4, Folder 70)
      writings (documents); Barns
    - "Benevolent Associations [Management of]", undated; 1982-0002/Series2:Writings/Box4:71 (Box-folder 4:71)
      Charities; writings (documents)
    - Connecticut, 1905; 1982-0002/Series2:Writings/Box4:72 (Box-folder 4:72)
      writings (documents); Connecticut (state)
    - "Cornwall, [Historical records of], 1904 (Box 4:, Folder 73)
    - Dairy farming, 1877-1880; 1982-0002/Series2:Writings/Box5:74 (Box 5, Folder 74)
      writings (documents); Dairy farming
    - "Habits of Manners", undated; 1982-0002/SeriesII:Writings/Box5:75 (Box 5, Folder 75)
      Manners and customs
    - Handbook of Connecticut Agriculture, 1901; 1982-0002/Series2:Writings/Box5:76 (Box 5:, Folder 76)
      Books.; Agriculture; Connecticut (state)
    - "Historical Notes", 1905; 1982-0002/Series2:Writings/Box5:77 (Box 5, Folder 77)
    - "A History of the Connecticut Agricultural College", manuscript, 1902; 1982-0002/Series2:Writings/Box5:78 (Box-folder 5:78)
      Manuscripts (document genre); Universities and colleges; Connecticut Agricultural College
    - "A History of the Connecticut Agricultural College", typescript, 1902; 1982-0002/SeriesII:Writings/Box5:79 (Box-folder 5:79)
      Storrs (inhabited place); Connecticut (state); Universities and colleges; writings (documents); Typescripts; Connecticut Agricultural College
    - "A History of the Connecticut Agricultural College", typescript (duplicate with handwritten notations), 1982-0002/SeriesII:Writings/Box5:79a (Box-folder 5:79a)
      Universities and colleges
    - "Reminiscences", undated; 1982-0002/SeriesII:Writings/Box5:80 (Box 5, Folder 80)
    - "Reminiscences: An address at...", 1901; 1982-0002/Series2:Writings/Box5:81 (Box 5:, Folder 81)
      writings (documents); Reminiscing; reminiscences
    - "Rural Rambles", undated; 1982-0002/SeriesII:Writings/Box5:82 (Box 5, Folder 82)
      Country life; Farm life; Connecticut (state)
    - Science Relative to Agriculture, undated; 1982-0002/SeriesII:Writings/Box5:83 (Box-folder 5:83, Box 5:, Folder 83)
      Agriculture
    - Sheep, 1851-1898; 1982-0002/Series2:Writings/Box5:84 (Box-folder 5:84)
      Sheep; Manuscripts (document genre); Connecticut (state)
    - Sheep, 1851-1898; 1982-0002/SeriesII:Writings/Box5:85 (Box-folder 5:85)
      Manuscripts (document genre); Connecticut (state); Sheep
    - Trees and Forestry, 1880-1897; 1982-0002/SeriesII:Writings/Box5:86 (Box-folder 5:86, Box 5:, Folder 86)
      Connecticut (state); Trees; Forests and forestry; Manuscripts (document genre)
  - Storrs Agricultural School
    - Deed, copy, 1887 March (Box 6:, Folder 87)
    - Cost estimate, 1884-1885 (Box 6:, Folder 88)
    - [George] Flint address, 1899 December (Box 6:, Folder 89)
    - Printed material, undated (Box 6:, Folder 90)
    - Trustee certificates, 1884-1897 (Box 6:, Folder 91)
  - Personal Memorabilia
    - Certificates of membership, 1876-1902 (Box 6:, Folder 92)
    - Math copybook, undated (Box 6:, Folder 93)
    - Photographs
      - Agriculture, undated (Box 6:, Folder 94)
      - Buildings, undated (Box 6:, Folder 95)
      - T.S. Gold, undated (Box 6:, Folder 96)
      - Personal, undated (Box 6:, Folder 97)
      - Trees, undated (Box 6:, Folder 98)
    - Glass plate negative, undated (Box 6:, Folder 99)
    - Engravings, undated (Box 6:, Folder 100)
    - Etchings, civil war generals, undated (Box 6:, Folder 101)
    - Newsclippings, undated (Box 6:, Folder 102)
  - Business
    - Receipts, 1859-1880 (Box 6:, Folder 103)
    - Receipts, 1881-1904 (Box 6:, Folder 104)
    - Bills, 1869-1885 (Box 6:, Folder 105)
    - Land surveys, undated (Box 6:, Folder 106)
    - Housatonic Valley Milk Association records, undated (Box 6:, Folder 107)
    - H. Schafer milk statements, 1870-1873 (Box 7:, Folder 108)
  - Printed Material
    - Goodwins Annual Legislative Statistics, 1876 (Box 7:, Folder 109)
    - Goodwins Annual Legislative Statistics, 1877-1885 (Box 7:, Folder 110)
    - American Pomological Society, undated (Box 7:, Folder 111)
    - Housatonic Valley Milk Association, undated (Box 7:, Folder 112)
    - American Dariymen's Association centennial exhibit, 1876 (Box 7:, Folder 113)
    - World's Exposition, 1884-1885 (Box 7:, Folder 114)
    - Ontario Agricultural College and Agricultural Station, undated (Box 7:, Folder 115)
    - Yale University, undated (Box 7:, Folder 116)
    - Agriculture - Connecticut, undated (Box 7:, Folder 117)
    - Agriculture - outside Connecticut, undated (Box 7:, Folder 118-123)
    - N.Y. agricultural editorial by E.T. Gold, undated (Box 8:, Folder 124)
    - Connecticut Soldiers' Orphans' Home, undated (Box 8:, Folder 125-126)
    - Reports
      - Railroad tables, undated (Box 8:, Folder 127-128)
      - Religious, undated (Box 8:, Folder 129-131)
      - Sons of the American Revolution, undated (Box 8:, Folder 132)
      - Connecticut Humane Society, undated (Box 8:, Folder 133)
      - Schools in Connecticut, undated (Box 8:, Folder 134)
      - Connecticut historical sites and parks, undated (Box 8:, Folder 135)
      - Connecticut Hospital for the Insane, undated (Box 8:, Folder 136)
      - Connecticut groups and associations, undated (Box 8:, Folder 137)
      - Clubs, associations, societies, undated (Box 8:, Folder 138)
      - Schools, colleges, universities, undated (Box 8:, Folder 139)
      - General information, advertisements, undated (Box 9:, Folder 140)
      - Genealogical services, undated (Box 9:, Folder 141)
      - General printed items, undated (Box 9:, Folder 142-143)
      - Events, undated (Box 9:, Folder 144)
      - Wood Printing Block "Old Cheshire Apple Tree", undated (Box 9:, Folder 145)
      - Stamps, undated (Box 9:, Folder 146)
  - Condolences
    - Condolences, 1906 (Box 9:, Folder 147-151)
- Series II: Gold Family, 1809-1907
  - Gold Family
    - Gold/Cleveland family history, undated (Box 10:, Folder 152-154)
    - Gold family memorabilia, undated (Box 10:, Folder 155)
    - Gold family crest - glass photo plate, undated (Box 10:, Folder 156)
    - Gold/Cleveland family letters, 1830-1840 (Box 10:, Folder 157)
    - Deeds, indentures, undated (Box 10:, Folder 158)
  - Hezikiah Gold
    - Bills, 1800-1827 (Box 10:, Folder 159-160)
    - Correspondence: incoming, 1833-1836 (Box 10:, Folder 161)
    - Correspondence: incoming, 1837-1847 (Box 10:, Folder 162)
  - Phoebe Gold
    - Correspondence: incoming, 1823-1950 (Box 10:, Folder 163)
  - Dr. Samuel Wadsworth Gold, MD
    - Correspondence: incoming, undated (Box 11:, Folder 164)
    - Correspondence: incoming, 1809-1814 (Box 11:, Folder 165)
    - Correspondence: incoming, 1815-1831 (Box 11:, Folder 166)
    - Correspondence: incoming, 1833-1839 (Box 11:, Folder 167)
    - Correspondence: incoming, 1840-1864 (Box 11:, Folder 168)
    - Bills and notes, undated (Box 11:, Folder 169)
    - Sunday school lessons and notes, undated (Box 11:, Folder 170)
    - Printed items by Dr. Gold, undated (Box 11:, Folder 171)
    - Drafts of letters, undated (Box 11:, Folder 172-175)
  - Charles L. Gold
    - Ephemera, undated (Box 11:, Folder 176)
  - Franz Ulrich Von Puttkamer
    - Von Puttkamer estate papers, 1889 (Box 12:, Folder 177)
    - Von Puttkamer estate papers, 1890 (Box 12:, Folder 178)
    - Von Puttkamer estate papers, 1891 January - May (Box 12:, Folder 179)
    - Von Puttkamer estate papers, 1891 June - December (Box 12:, Folder 180)
    - Von Puttkamer estate papers, 1892 January - June (Box 12:, Folder 181)
    - Von Puttkamer estate papers, 1892 July (Box 12:, Folder 182)
    - Von Puttkamer estate papers, 1892 August (Box 12:, Folder 183)
    - Von Puttkamer estate papers, 1892 September (Box 12:, Folder 184)
    - Von Puttkamer estate papers, 1892 October (Box 12:, Folder 185)
    - Von Puttkamer estate papers, 1892 November (Box 12:, Folder 186)
    - Von Puttkamer estate papers, 1892 December (Box 12:, Folder 187)
    - Von Puttkamer estate papers, 1893 January - February (Box 12:, Folder 188)
    - Von Puttkamer estate papers, 1893 March - May (Box 12:, Folder 189)
    - Von Puttkamer estate papers, 1893 June - December (Box 12:, Folder 190)
    - Von Puttkamer estate papers, 1894 January - June (Box 13:, Folder 191)
    - Von Puttkamer estate papers, 1894 July - December (Box 13:, Folder 192)
    - Von Puttkamer estate papers, 1895 (Box 13:, Folder 193)
    - Von Puttkamer estate papers, 1896 (Box 13:, Folder 194)
    - Von Puttkamer estate papers, 1897 (Box 13:, Folder 195)
    - Von Puttkamer estate papers, 1898 (Box 13:, Folder 196)
    - Von Puttkamer estate papers, 1899 (Box 13:, Folder 197)
    - Von Puttkamer estate papers, 1900 (Box 13:, Folder 198)
    - Von Puttkamer estate papers, 1901-1902 (Box 13:, Folder 199)
    - Von Puttkamer estate papers, 1903 (Box 13:, Folder 200)
    - Von Puttkamer estate papers, 1904 (Box 13:, Folder 201)
    - Von Puttkamer estate papers, 1905 (Box 13:, Folder 202)
    - Von Puttkamer estate papers), 1906-1907 (Box 13:, Folder 203)
    - Deeds, undated (Box 13:, Folder 204)
    - Notes, undated (Box 13:, Folder 205)
    - Cancelled checks, undated (Box 13:, Folder 206)
    - Account books, undated (Box 13:, Folder 207)
  - General John Sedgwich
    - Letters to sister, 1847-1862 (Box 14:, Folder 208)
    - Letters to sister, 1863 (Box 14:, Folder 209)
    - Letters to sister, 1864 (Box 14:, Folder 210)
    - Letters to parents, 1839-1856 (Box 14:, Folder 211)
    - Memorial service, printed items, 1892 (Box 14:, Folder 212-214)
    - Memorial service, orders and receipts, 1892 (Box 14:, Folder 215-218)
    - Memorial service, invitation responses, 1892 (Box 15:, Folder 219-224)
- Series III: Newspapers, 1800-1901
  - Boston Daily Globe, 1881 September 27 (Box 16:, Folder 225)
  - Boston Journal, 1881 October 7 (Box 16:, Folder 226)
  - Brooklyn Daily Eagle, 1884 September 4 (Box 16:, Folder 227)
  - The Christian Mirror, 1892 December 3 (Box 16:, Folder 228)
  - Cleveland Weekly Herald, 1867 November 30 (Box 16:, Folder 229)
  - Cleveland Weekly Herald, 1883 January 24 (Box 16:, Folder 229)
  - The College Courant, 1873 July 12 (Box 16:, Folder 230)
  - Colman's Rural World, 1873 Jul 19 (Box 16:, Folder 231)
  - Colman's Rural World, 1883 August 2 (Box 16:, Folder 231)
  - Colonel Pickering's Letter, 1808 February 16 (Box 16:, Folder 232)
  - The Connecticut Farmer (Box 16:, Folder 233-235)
    - 1880 January 3
    - 1881 December 10
    - 1881 December 31
    - 1882 July 8
    - 1882 July 15
    - 1892 June 25
    - 1892 December 31
    - 1893 January 2
    - 1906 July 14
  - The Connecticut Press, [1860s] (Box 16:, Folder 236)
  - Cranium Gazette, undated (Box 16:, Folder 237)
  - The Cultivator's Guide, 1883 December (Box 16:, Folder 238)
  - The Daily Real Estate Reporter, undated (Box 16:, Folder 239)
  - The Dairyman, 1888 November 7 (Box 16:, Folder 240)
  - The Hartford Courant (Box 16-17:, Folder 241-246)
    - 1882 September 8
    - 1882 September 15
    - 1882 September 22
    - 1892 September 13
    - 1892 September 27
    - 1894 November 14
    - 1895 July 13
    - 1895 November 5
    - 1897 August 3
    - 1901 January 1
  - Hartford Daily Courant, 1866 October 4 (Box 17:, Folder 247)
  - Hartford Daily Courant, 1901 December 17 (Box 17:, Folder 248)
  - Hartford Evening Post, 1885 January 7 (Box 17:, Folder 249)
  - Hartford Evening Press, 1866 October 4 (Box 17:, Folder 250)
  - The Independent (Box 17:, Folder 251)